<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>STRUDEL</title>
    <description>The Socio-Technical Research Using Data Excavation Lab at Carnegie Mellon University</description>
    <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://cmustrudel.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 01:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 01:29:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: CMU trivia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To prepare myself for next year’s SCS trivia and to demonstrate my school pride,
I set up a one trivia a day challenge for myself. 
My plan is to continue this until I leave CMU.
All the trivias will be related to CMU or Computer Science in general. 
This year’s SCS trivia night made me realize how little I know about female
computer scientist, so I will focus
more on this part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned many of Computer Science related trivia from “Great Moments in
Computing”, a great course offered at
Princeton University taught by Professor Maragret Martonosi.
Many CMU related trivias are learned by wandering in campus during work breaks.
If you spot any mistakes in this post, please email me: hsqq at cmu dot edu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hello-world&quot;&gt;Hello, world!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;March 23, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let the first trivia be our most familiar program, &lt;b&gt;hello world&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dr. Dennis Ritchie&lt;/b&gt; developed the language &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;, which he used to
implement the operating system &lt;b&gt;Unix&lt;/b&gt; with &lt;b&gt;Ken Thompson&lt;/b&gt;.
To educate people how to use C, 
&lt;b&gt;Dr. Brian Kernighan&lt;/b&gt; wrote the textbook &lt;i&gt;The C Programming Language&lt;/i&gt; 
and used the program hello world as an introductory example. This was the first
apperance of the hello world program. 
Ever since then, most beginners’ first program in many languages have been some
variation of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;main()

{

  printf(&quot;hello, world\n&quot;);

}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Brian Kernighan is now a professor at &lt;b&gt;Princeton University&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;multics&quot;&gt;MULTICS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;March 24, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I want to talk about Unix, the operating system developed with C.
But before I can get to Unix itself, I want to briefly introduce
its predecessor, MULTICS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Unix, there was an operating system called &lt;b&gt;MULTICS&lt;/b&gt;(&lt;b&gt;Mult&lt;/b&gt;iplexed
&lt;b&gt;I&lt;/b&gt;nformation and &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;omputing &lt;b&gt;S&lt;/b&gt;ervice), developed by &lt;b&gt;MIT, GE,
and Bell Lab&lt;/b&gt; and released in &lt;b&gt;1969&lt;/b&gt;.
You can read the original paper here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.classes.cs.uchicago.edu/archive/2017/fall/33100-1/papers/multics.pdf&quot;&gt;Virtual
Memory, Processes, and Sharing in MULTICS&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;b&gt;Robert C. Daley and Jack B.
Dennis&lt;/b&gt;.
The main concepts introduced with MULTICS are &lt;b&gt;Proccess&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Address
space&lt;/b&gt;.
Quoting from the paper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Processes stand in one-to-one correspondence
with virtual memories. Each process runs in
its own address space, which is established independently
of other address spaces. Processes are run on a processor
at the discretion of the traffic controller module of the
supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These concepts are still prevalent today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;unix&quot;&gt;UNIX&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;March 25, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;b&gt;UNIX&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name UNIX stands for &lt;i&gt;Uniplexed Infromation and Computing Service&lt;/i&gt; and
it was suggested by Dr. Brian Kernighan in 1970.
It was developed by &lt;b&gt;Ken Thompson, Dennis Ritchie, Brian Kernighan, Douglas
Mcllroy, and Joe Ossanna&lt;/b&gt; at &lt;b&gt;Bell Labs&lt;/b&gt;.
The design of UNIX is summarized in &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.eecs.berkeley.edu/~brewer/cs262/unix.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The UNIX
Time-Sharing System&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and published in &lt;b&gt;1974&lt;/b&gt;, 6 years after MULTICS.
I highly recommend reading this paper for it is a well-written paper and you
will be able to understand how clever the system was designed so that its
essence has not varied too much since its birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1974 version of UNIX contained only 11K lines of code for the kernel (for
your reference, 2017 Linux kernel 4.1.38 contains ~5.4M lines of code).
One of the biggest difference between MULTICS and UNIX is that data on MULTICS
are stored in address, which allows random access, whereas in UNIX, data are stored in file, which is an
abstraction that allows user to handle hardware, directories, and normal files
in the same way be it random or sequential access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Dennis Ritchie and Ken Thompson won &lt;b&gt;Turing Award&lt;/b&gt; in &lt;b&gt;1983&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;alan-turing&quot;&gt;Alan Turing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;March 26, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting from today, I would like to talk about Turing Award, the most
prestigious award in the field of Computer Science.
But before I introduce any of Turing Award Winner, let me first talk about Alan
M. Turing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dr. Turing&lt;/b&gt; received his Ph.D. from &lt;b&gt;Princeton&lt;/b&gt;, where he spent only
&lt;b&gt;two years&lt;/b&gt;.
Unlike some people who drop out from grad college after two years, Dr. Turing
had earned his Ph.D. within those two years.
One of Turing’s  most famous contributions should be his &lt;b&gt;Turing test&lt;/b&gt;,
which he originally called “the imitation game” introduced in his paper &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://phil415.pbworks.com/f/TuringComputing.pdf&quot;&gt;MIND
a quarterly review of psychology and philosophy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; in 1950, only 4 years after
the birth of ENIAC.
Turing is also known for his &lt;b&gt;lambda calculus&lt;/b&gt;, co-developed with his Ph.D.
advisor Alonzo Church, and &lt;b&gt;Turing Machine&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;turing-award-at-cmu&quot;&gt;Turing Award at CMU&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick trivia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-turing.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;alan-perlis-1966&quot;&gt;Alan Perlis, 1966.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;March 27, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to say that before I introduce Turing Award winners from the
earliest to the most recent, I would like to priotize those were or still are
related to CMU. However, I just learned that the first Turing Award winner was
the first head of our Computer Science Department at CMU, &lt;b&gt;Alan Perlis&lt;/b&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Perlis made incredible amount of contribution to the field of computer
science.
He participated in the designing and building of some of the earliest electrical
computers. He also helped design &lt;b&gt;IBM 650&lt;/b&gt;. Together with Simon and Newell, he defined
the term &lt;b&gt;“computer science”&lt;/b&gt; to be “the theory and design of computers.”
In 1961, he taught the &lt;b&gt;first freshman-level computer science course&lt;/b&gt; in the nation at
Carnegie Tech, which later merged with Mellon Institute to form CMU.
In 1965, Computer Science Department was esablished and he became the first
head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;allen-newell-and-herbert-simon-1975&quot;&gt;Allen Newell and Herbert Simon, 1975.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;March 28, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Herbert Alexander Simon was a professor in &lt;b&gt;Political Science&lt;/b&gt;. 
His insight of human decision making lead to his development of &lt;b&gt;heuristic
programming&lt;/b&gt;.
Dr. Simon’s research interests are AI, simulation, software design, and HCI, all
of which are still CMU’s strongest fields.
Dr. Simon also won the Nobel Prize in Economics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Newell earned his Ph.D. degree at CMU Tepper School advised by Dr. Simon. 
Together with his advisor Dr. Simon, they worked on heuristic programming and
created the first AI program, &lt;b&gt;Logic Theorist&lt;/b&gt;.
He spent a year at Princeton where he worked on game theory which influenced his
later work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newell, Simon, and Perlis created Computer Science Department together in
&lt;b&gt;1965&lt;/b&gt;.
The building, Newell Simon Hall, for Human Computer Interaction Institute and Robotics Institute is
named after Dr. Newell and Dr. Simon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dana-stewart-scott-and-michael-o-rabin-1976&quot;&gt;Dana Stewart Scott and Michael O. Rabin, 1976.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;March 29, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Scott and Dr. Rabin jointly developed the idea of &lt;b&gt;nondeterministic
machines&lt;/b&gt; in the paper “Finite Automata and Their Decision Problem”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Scott earned his BA at Berkeley and his Ph.D. at Princeton. 
After jumping around multiple top universities, in 1981, he came to CMU and
became a professor of Computer Science, Mathematical Logic, and Philosophy. 
He took the position of Hillman Professor of Computer Science. 
Dr. Scott is also famous for his contribution to computer programming language
analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Rabin also earned his Ph.D. at Princeton in Mathematics. 
He is famous for his idea of adding randomness to algorithm.
His later work concerns cryptographic problems and helped develop a
zero-knowledge proof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;robert-floyd-1978&quot;&gt;Robert Floyd, 1978.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;March 30, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Floyd received his Turing Award “for having a clear influence on
methodologies for the creation of efficient and reliable software, and for
helping to found the following important subfields of computer science: the
theory of parsing, the semantics of programming languages, automatic program
verification, automatic program synthesis, and analysis of algorithms.”
Floyd did not get a Ph.D.
However, he was appointed an associated professor at CMU when he was at the age
of 27 and, six years later, became a full professor at Stanford University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ivan-sutherland-1988&quot;&gt;Ivan Sutherland, 1988.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;March 31, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ivan Sutherland earned his Bachelors of Science Degree from CMU, which was
Carnegie Institute of Technology back then. After he earned his Master of
Science Degree from California Institute of Technology in 1960, he went to MIT where he
worked with &lt;b&gt;Dr. Claude Shannon&lt;/b&gt; and earned his Ph.D. within 3 years.
His Ph.D. thesis “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/techreports/UCAM-CL-TR-574.pdf&quot;&gt;Sketchpad: A
Man-machine Graphical Communications System&lt;/a&gt;” introduced &lt;b&gt;Sketchpad&lt;/b&gt;, the first computer graphics software.
Sketchpad was developed on the TX-2, which was one of the first transistor-based
computers with core memory. 
To use the Sketchpad, one needs to hold a lightpen, which, instead of emitting
lights as our mouses today, senses lights from the screen and determine the
pointing location.
The shapes drawn are stored like objects as in the notion of object-oriented
programming with the capability of creating
multiple identical but distinct copies and modifying each one of them
separately. 
A demo by Dr. Sutherland can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=57wj8diYpgY&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=57wj8diYpgY&lt;/a&gt;
His work is considered to be the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: Dr. Claude Shannon was the advisor of Ivan Sutherland and his older
brother, Bert Sutherland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;d-waitzman&quot;&gt;D. Waitzman&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 1, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D. Waitzman won some award (whatever it is) for his contribution in &lt;b&gt;IP over Avian Carriers
(IPoAC)&lt;/b&gt;. It is originally described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1149&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;A Standard for the Transimission
of IP Datagrams on Avian Carriers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
This system can in theory achieve 145.6Gbit/s transfer rate but the packet loss
can be as high as 55%. Security is another weakness of IPoAC. Therefore, if you
are concerned about packet loss and security issues, don’t use this method.
Otherwise, it can be one of the fastest way of getting a huge amount of data
transferred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine at Princeton once implemented a method that could transfer 1TB
data within half an hour with 0 packet loss.
He is not a student in computer science. He studies physics and mainly writes
code in FORTRAN.
His system is also highly secure with 0 information leekage - he drove to his lab and retrieved
his hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;edward-feigenbaum-and-raj-reddy-1994&quot;&gt;Edward Feigenbaum and Raj Reddy, 1994&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 2, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They won Turing Award for their contribution in building large scale AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Edward Feigenbaum is known as the father of &lt;b&gt;Expert Systems&lt;/b&gt;.
Dr. Feigenbaum earned is B.S. in Electrical Engineering at CMU where he took Dr.
Simon’s course on Mathematical Models in the Social Sciences and got his first
taste of computer science by studying Simon’s manual for IBM 701.
After he earned his B.S., he continuted for a Ph.D. at CMU with Dr. Simon on
building &lt;b&gt;a model that simulates how human learn nonsense syllables&lt;/b&gt;.
This model stores data with a decision tree, which he called &lt;b&gt;Discrimiation
Net&lt;/b&gt;.
It is interesting to see how our founders research interests are still carried
on by today’s CMU researchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;manuel-blum-1995&quot;&gt;Manuel Blum, 1995&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 3, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Blum is currently a professor at CMU. 
He won his Turing Award for “his contributions to the foundations of &lt;b&gt;computational
complexity theory&lt;/b&gt; and its application to &lt;b&gt;cryptography and program
checking&lt;/b&gt;.”
I just checked his website, he recently taught courses on undergraduate
complexity theory and intro to cryptography.
One of his great contributions is an algorithm that can find the median of a
sequence of numbers in linear time.
Fun fact: His wife is a distinguished professor at CMU SCS - &lt;b&gt;Lenore Blum&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;jonh-hennessy-and-david-patterson-2018&quot;&gt;Jonh Hennessy and David Patterson, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;June 4, 2018&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. John L. Hennessy used to be the &lt;b&gt;President of Stanford&lt;/b&gt; and Dr. David A.
Patterson retired from &lt;b&gt;UC Berkeley&lt;/b&gt;. 
They are both rewarded the Turing Award for their contribution to a systematic,
quantitative approch to the design and evaluation of computer architectures. 
They wrote a very influencial textbook, &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Computer Architecture: A Quantitative
Approach&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, which is still used today by many computer architecture courses
(and I still have a copy of it).
I was lucky enough to attend Dr. Patterson’s talk on &lt;b&gt;RISC V&lt;/b&gt; at Princeton two years ago -
I’m a big fan of RISC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 17:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/cmu/CMUtrivia</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/cmu/CMUtrivia</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>CMU</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: STRUDEL Reading Group Updates</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-may-23-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, May 23, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks’ practice talks, Sophie Qiu, yes, her again, presented the
paper &lt;b&gt;Newcomers’ Barriers. . . Is That All? An Analysis of Mentors’ and
Newcomers’ Barriers in OSS Projects&lt;/b&gt; (Balali et al., CSCW, 2018).
The paper identified several barriers that mentors are facing in open source
software projects. There are many newly found barriers but I think some of them
can be combined with or subsumed under some old ones; some need more details or
real instances. 
I think the barriers that they had identified are important.
However, I wish to see more practical and concrete solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-april-25-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, April 25, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie Qiu presented the freshly baked paper &lt;b&gt;Competence-Confidence Gap: A
Threat to Female Developers’ Contribution on GitHub&lt;/b&gt; (Wang et al., ICSE,
2018).
The authors show that there is a Granger causality between female programmers’ raise of number
of followers and their pull requests on GitHub. They claim that this is because
the number of followers bridges women’s competence-confidence gap and reassures 
female programmer that their contribution will be welcomed and
valuable.
Although this sounds a potential solution to encourage women to make
contributions to open source softwares, the paper did not mention how these
woemn earned new followers in the first place. The only example vaguely
mentioned was that the female programmer looked cute, which is in fact not an
acknowledgement of her programming ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-april-4-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, April 4, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alan Jaffe presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://victorialin.net/pubs/tellina_tr_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;Program Synthesis from Natural Language Using
Recurrent Neural Networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Lin et al., UW-CSE, 2017).
We often say there are two major coding styles: stackoverflow oriented
programming and google oriented programming.
The point it is making is that all the code we need are written, programmers
only need to assemble them to make a executable program.
I believe this can be easily replaced by machines and this paper is a proof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-march-28-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, March 28, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marat Valiet presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1802.07068.pdf&quot;&gt;Talent vs Luck: the role of
randomness in success and failure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.
This paper is a cool example of using simulation to address real life problems.
With a simple design they were able to model different funding policies and
their outcome. The paper claims that in some setups with a large influence of
luck, strategies based on random choices are more effective than traditional
“naively meritocratic” models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow people had forgotten our good tradition of bringing snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-march-21-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, March 21, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bogdan Vasilescu presented the paper &lt;b&gt;Was my contribution fairly
reviewed?” A Framework to Study the Perception of Fairness in Modern Code
Reviews&lt;/b&gt; (Yang, ICSE, 2018). In the paper, many different aspects of fairness are discussed,
which was very inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-feburary-21-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, Feburary 21, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Lacomis presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hal.inria.fr/hal-01691496/file/SEIP_63_Camera-Ready-no-copyright.pdf&quot;&gt;How
to Design a Program Repair Bot? Insights from
the Repairnator Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Urli et al. ICSE 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to learn about online program repair bugs. When I was talking
with a CMU undergrad at one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/cmukgb/&quot;&gt;KGB&lt;/a&gt;’s activity, he was excited
to learn that people are working on how to fix bugs automatically since he has
some very unpleasant experience with debugging - so do many of us. It would be
great if we could have a bug repairing bot with high accuracy in the future.
However, as Marat pointed out, when the debugging process can be largely
substituted by a robot, that means this language is dying. One example is
Assembly. Here’s a quote from Paul Graham
about the evolution of programming languages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What programmers in a hundred years will be looking for, most of all, is a
language where you can throw together an unbelievably inefficient version 1 of a
program with the least possible effort. At least, that’s how we’d describe it in
present-day terms. What they’ll say is that they want a language that’s easy to
program in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inefficient software isn’t gross. What’s gross is a language that makes
programmers do needless work. Wasting programmer time is the true inefficiency,
not wasting machine time. This will become ever more clear as computers get
faster.” (source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/hundred.html&quot;&gt;http://www.paulgraham.com/hundred.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-feburary-14-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, Feburary 14, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Yanwen Lin presented the paper
&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://haiyizhu.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/predicting-member-productivity-1.pdf&quot;&gt;Predicting
Member Productivity and Withdrawal from
Pre-Joining Attachments in Online Production Groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Yu et al. CSCW 17).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper analysed withdrawl from Wikipedia groups using the attachment
theories from social psychology. 
There results show that pre-joining connections are important to online
production groups. Speaking from my personal experience, I totally agree with
the authors. Especially in online community, when you often interact with people
who you don’t konw much personal information, it can be hard to form attachment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-feburary-7-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, Feburary 7, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shurui Zhou presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gustavopinto.org/lost+found/icse2018.pdf&quot;&gt;Almost There: A Study on
Quasi-Contributors in Open-Source Software Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Steinmarcher et al.,
ICSE 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to learn that many people stopped making further
contribution on GitHub after their first pull request was rejected. We also felt
that there would be many future work worth pursuing. Thanks Shurui’s
presentation as well as her snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was Alex’s meeting before he became a
professor in Estonia, he also brought some
pastries from Gates. We appreciated his intention of getting us fat. We will
miss you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, I think Gates’ blueberry muffin is very nice, as well as banana &amp;amp;
nuts in Scott. Nevertheless, no muffin compares to thos in Brown’s Blue Room or
banana muffin at Corner Bakery Cafe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-janurary-14-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, Janurary 14, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Widder presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ir.library.oregonstate.edu/downloads/wh246x964&quot;&gt;Open Source
barriers to entry, revisited: A tools perspective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Mendez et al. ICSE 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Margaret Burnett’s team has been studying GitHub’s gender inclusive
issues. Since men and women are biologically different statistically, tools
should be designed to cater their different ways of thinking and engaging with
software. I do not think software developing is an inheritly male dominated task. I
believe that getting
more women into software developing is a key to gender equality. Yes, I am a
feminist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davis is very good at baking, but I think he should have given out his delicious
brownies at the beginning of his presentation rather than at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;thusday-december-5-2017&quot;&gt;Thusday, December 5, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie Qiu presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1071581916301033&quot;&gt;The influence of visual feedback and
gender dynamics on performance,
perception and communication strategies in CSCW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Koulouri et al.
International Journal of Human-Computer Studies 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper shows that while men are statistically better at navigation with help
from visual signals, women can use verbal communication to compensate such
weakness and achieve the same level of excellency in navitation tasks.
GenderMag, which David Widder will present later, is in the same mindset that
although men and women are statistically biologically different, well-designed
tools can help both of them succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie did not know that green been pie could contain cream so she bought a lot
of them. Luckily, she could bring them to Strudel meetings so that everyone can
eat them and be merry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-28-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 28, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bogdan Vasilescu presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8031982/&quot;&gt;Code Coverage and Postrelease
Defects: A Large-Scale Study on Open Source Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Kochhar et al. 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper shows that code coverage in testing has insignificant correlation
with the number of bugs at the project level of a software. Then my question
was: how much test would be sufficient if a large software project could never be
bug-free?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not remember what snack we had during that meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-21-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 21, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shurui Zhou presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3104225&quot;&gt;Some from here, some from
there: cross-project code reuse in GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Gharehyazie et al., MSR 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper reminds me of two most popular ways of coding: Google-oriented coding
and stackoverflow-oriented coding. It is expensive to write code from scratch,
so understanding how code pieces are cloned across projects is useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not quite remember the snack but it might be Shurui’s Choco Pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-14-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 14, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexander Nolte presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hci.stanford.edu/publications/2017/flashorgs/flash-orgs-chi-2017.pdf&quot;&gt;Flash Organizations:
Crowdsourcing Complex Work by Structuring Crowds As Organizations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a nice paper on how to more effectively form an software developing group.
It was good to read some paper on HCI, which I was fascinated in but knew very
little about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your cookies, Alex. I guess they came from La Prima Espresso in
WEAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-7-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 7, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alan Jaffe presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1708.09492.pdf&quot;&gt;Automatically Generating Commit Messages
from Diffs Using Neural Machine Translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Jiang et al., ASE
2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an interesting application of the naturalness of code. I
learned a lot about the idea of naturalness of code, as well as the fact
that Alan is very good at baking pumpkin pies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-31-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 31, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No meeting this week. STRUDEL was away attending 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://ase2017.org&quot;&gt;ASE&lt;/a&gt; in Urbana-Champaign, IL and visiting
Fiona at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/cincinnatizoo/&quot;&gt;Cincinnati Zoo&lt;/a&gt;.
#teamfiona&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/10-31-17-fiona.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-24-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 24, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STRUDEL was proud to host &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.win.tue.nl/~aserebre/&quot;&gt;Alexander 
Serebrenik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; from TU Eindhoven, who talked about his recent work on mining 
emotions from software engineering artifacts.
We were all enjoying his talk as well as Sophie’s hazelnut wafel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/10-24-17-serebrenik.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-17-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 17, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~fmri/plosone/files/hp_PLOS_ONE.pdf&quot;&gt;Simultaneously
Uncovering the Patterns of
Brain Regions Involved in Different Story
Reading Subprocesses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Wehbe et al., PLoS ONE 2014).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers scanned participants brains while they were reading
the ninth chapter of &lt;i&gt;Harry Potter and the Sorcerer’s Stone&lt;/i&gt;. They
then trained a classifier that can distinguish which short passage the
participants were reading based on the neural activity. The choice of
this paper was to present group members another machine learning
classifier that can process fMRI results. 
It was very nice and sweet that David made apple raisin strudels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/10-17-17-strudel.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-10-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 10, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marat presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://delivery.acm.org/10.1145/2540000/2531642/p831-backstrom.pdf?ip=24.238.13.130&amp;amp;id=2531642&amp;amp;acc=OA&amp;amp;key=4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E528920FC4509E774&amp;amp;CFID=993659916&amp;amp;CFTOKEN=60398709&amp;amp;__acm__=1509333674_18432c45ea35e7515bb15ff9492d27f0&quot;&gt;Romantic partnerships and the
dispersion of social ties: a network analysis of relationship status on
facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Backstrom et al, CSCW 2014).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper proposed to use
dispersion, which measures “the extent to which two people’s mutual
friends are not themselves well-connected,” in addition to embeddedness,
which measures the number of mutural friends, to predict if two Facebook users 
are in a romantic relationship. The accuracy of prediction increased 
significantly when using the dispersion metric.
Somehow, my impression of the paper smells like homemade banana bread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-3-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 3, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://yuchi1989.github.io/papers/fse17-ErrDoc.pdf&quot;&gt;Automatically
Diagnosing and Repairing Error Handling Bugs in C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Tian and Ray, ESEC/FSE 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper presents how to identify different types of bugs and how to correct
them in C/C++ code. 
Happy Mid-autumn festival and thanks Sophie for her mooncake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/10-03-17-moon.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-september-26-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, September 26, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.eecs.umich.edu/~weimerw/p/weimer-icse2017-preprint.pdf&quot;&gt;Decoding the representation of code in the
brain: An fMRI study of code review and expertise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Floyd et al, ICSE 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers scanned participants’ brain while they were reviewing code or 
prose. The findings suggest that reading code differs from reading natural 
language, but less so for experts than for novices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-september-19-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, September 19, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had our first reading group meeting today! To celebrate, Bogdan brought 
apple-cinnamon strudels for us. Nevertheless, these strudles were not as
good as our discussion on the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.cs.umass.edu/~ameli/projects/fairness/papers/discriminationTesting.pdf&quot;&gt;Fairness Testing: 
Testing Software for Discrimination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Galhotra et al, ESEC/FSE 2017) that 
Bogdan presented at the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/09-19-17-group.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/reading-group-meeting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/reading-group-meeting</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>reading-group</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Life @ CMU</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I came to the Open House in March 2017, I found that CMU is a nerdy but
cool space. 
I’m writing down things I find interesting here.
Hope this blog can tell you more about CMU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;may-25-2018&quot;&gt;May 25, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-high-five.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are we suppose to high five whenever we go pass by this sign, like you have to
kiss if you stand under a mistletoe??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-superstar.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time I see this sign, I always think of the song Super Star by a Taiwanese
girls group S.H.E. This is one of the earliest pop songs I heard in my life. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gr5fNKK2FaA&quot;&gt;Click here to watch the
official MV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;may-5-2018&quot;&gt;May 5, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-y-axis.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-yaxis-dissys.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wander around in GHC when I’m tired of working and I find many
interesting things on people’s office doors. 
For example, the image on the left reminds me of a class at Princeton. We were
reading papers on distributed system, and one graph, reproduced on the right,
compares existing systems and the one introduced in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.cornell.edu/projects/Quicksilver/public_pdfs/RIPQ.pdf&quot;&gt;the
paper&lt;/a&gt;. Our professor
said, “guys, always start your y-axis from 0. I first thought FIFO sucks, but it
actually has 25% hit rate.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;may-1-2018&quot;&gt;May 1, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-monitors.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-poem.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CMU students often do some weird things. For example, someone wrote down the
Chinese poem A Moonlit Night on the Spring River on Pausch Bridge (image on the
left). Or, someone moved their monitors out to work in the corridor. Inspired
by this, now I often bring my mechanical keyboard to work in Gates where sunlight is
abundant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apr-20-2018&quot;&gt;Apr 20, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-mobot-field.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-mobot-sign.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-mobot.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-mobot-small.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CMU’s spring carnival should be very nerdy and CS. Therefore, we have a mobot
competition. I’ve been wondering why there are these ugly lines in front of Wean
Hall. Now I know the answer! They are routes for robots to follow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The task of mobot includes following the white line and going through 13 or 14
arches. Along the way, there are slopes. Some parts of the white lines are
painted against light grey ground. Towards the end of the journey, the robot
needs to know that it should stick to the path on the right (as shown in the
image) because that’s where the arches are placed. Once your robot has pased 3
arches, you are qualified for cash rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the teams if formed by a CMU alumni and his son, who had participated in
previous year’s mobot already. They made it to the final part but the robot took
the wrong route and lost the track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also some college students participating. The robot in the last image
is one of the smallest robots I’ve seen so far. I don’t quite understand why he
built the robot so small. The obvious drawback is that once it detrails from the track, even
just for a tiny bit, it can never find it back, which is what happened to the
robot at the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apr-20-2018-1&quot;&gt;Apr 20, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-carnival-trio.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-fatlady.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-dunk.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-dunkandrew.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring carnival!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from those amusement park monsters, there are some benign activities. For
example, each student organization built their own exhibition pavalion. Many of
them have two floors! There’s one has Harry Potter theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another fun thing to do is to dunk a dean. Each dean from a college sits above a
small pool for half an hour waiting for people to dunk them into the water. Some
deans wear swimming suits, some wear normal suits, even with ties! However, our
own dean, Andrew Moore, being so CS, wore a white t-shirt, a blue shorts, and a
pair of orange socks!!! I donated $2 and got 4 balls, two of which hit the red
button and sent him down into the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apr-19-2018&quot;&gt;Apr 19, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-carnival.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-carnival2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be CMU’s spring carnival tomorrow.
Apparantly, CMU somehow magically moved an amusement park to the campus.
I usually go into Gates building right after I arrive at campus so I don’t
usually see what’s going on on campus greens. Now that I suddenly see these
large monsters poped up from nowhere, I have a feeling of distance, as though
the neon lights were coming from far, far away.
Neon lights often give me a sense of noisiness but this time they seem to be so
serene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apr-19-2018-1&quot;&gt;Apr 19, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-radio.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had the honour of staying in my department overnight. Nights at CMU are
never quiet. 
You might think it is because of Ph.D. students.
No. Ph.D. students usually croach in their own offices; you rarely see them
move.
It is our cleaning staffs that make the nights colourful! They start cleaning up
the building at midnight. When they work, they put a radio in the NSH Perlis
Atrium and plays music. I’m not an expert on music genre, so I only know they
are not pop music nor classics. Maybe some blues or jazz type of music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apr-18-2018&quot;&gt;Apr 18, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-coffee.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know how much coffee we consume each day?!
I saw the front desk person filled up the coffee bean tank at around 8am. This
photo was taken at 3~4pm. See how much coffee beans had gone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apr-10-2018&quot;&gt;Apr 10, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-wean.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I think CMU and I share the same sense of humour, I totally don’t get
CMU’s sense of aesthetic. For example, what have they done to the stairs in Wean
Hall?!!!?!?! I thought we had a design school?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, David had the completely oppsite opinion. He thought this looks like in
fairytale. But I don’t see any romance or elegance in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/05-25-18-wean2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ultralowres.com/wean/&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; webpage introduces the art
piece. This graph helped me understand the rational behind the design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t you think this looks like gradient fields?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mar-29-2018&quot;&gt;Mar 29, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/03-29-18-sigbovik1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/03-29-18-sigbovik2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Jeremy and Squares Lab whose paper ``COBOLd: Gobblin’ up
COBOL bugs for fun and profit’’ has won the Test of Time Positive
Record Award (whatever it means) in 12th SIGBOVIK conference at CMU!
There work demostrates that by randomly replacing or adding or deleting code
from COBOL can make you super rich! 
By super rich I meant being able to buy a huge island.
By a huge island I mean some country in the south hemisphere.
Jeremy also gave a wonderful demo at the conference (pic 2). 
The paper can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://sigbovik.org/2018/proceedings.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (page 138-143).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mar-25-2018&quot;&gt;Mar 25, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/03-25-18-sunset.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A SCS Trivia Night style question: Where was this photo taken?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mar-19-2018&quot;&gt;Mar 19, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In case of fire, do you use elevator.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/03-19-18-fire.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mar-18-2018&quot;&gt;Mar 18, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;His heart is at work.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most people were away last week because of the spring break, this guy sat
at the teaching common the entire week. Apparantly, his heart is at work.
A typical CMU student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/03-18-18-atwork1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/03-18-18-atwork2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mar-14-2018&quot;&gt;Mar 14, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Physicist Stephen Hawking died at the age of 76 on Pie Day&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the east coast was entering pie day, I heard that we lost Professor Stephen Hawking.
Pie day is special not only because it is 3.14. It is also Einstein’s birthday.
This year, it has also become Hawking’s death date.
I still remember, when Professor Hawking’s books were translated into Chinese,
TV programs were repeating over and over again that Profssor Hawking was born on
the day on which Galileo Galilei died. 
Maybe great minds are always connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Professor Hawking’s science, I thought of a comic
sticked outside the office of Professor Thomas Ferguson, who helped construct
Large Hadron Collider (LHC), in Wean Hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/03-14-18-lhc.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mar-2-2018&quot;&gt;Mar 2, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Harry Potter Shabbat&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was surprised by how often I could spot a Harry Potter related thing on CMU
campus. I was even more surprised when I found out that there would be a Harry
Potter themed shabbat at Hillel Jewish University Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived at the front desk, there was a “sorting hat” from which you can
draw an image of a house’s badge. This “sorting ceremony” decides which table
you will sit at. I was “sorted” into Ravenclaw, although I was wearing
Gryffindor gears. All three other houses’ tables are quickly filled, except for
ours. By the time dinner started, we only had 3 people. The organizer said,
“Maybe Ravenclaws are still studying.” That sounds like what CMU students are
doing all the time. No wonder most students in our Harry Potter course identify
them with Ravenclaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/03-02-18-hpshabbat1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/03-02-18-hpshabbat2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can never forget how delicious their bread was!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s a trivia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Name a jewish student at Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;feb-14-2018&quot;&gt;Feb 14, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Valentine’s Day @ CMU&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My office mate told us if you brought your laptop to the
bookstore, they would clean it for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/02-14-18-valentine.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People celebrate Valentine’s Day with their valentines. Same here at CMU.
However, CMU might have defined valentine slightly differently. It expanded the
concept beyond human beings. Apart from your collaborators, people usually
interact the most with their valentines. If we count objects as well, one’s laptop 
is definitely the number 1 valentine of most CMU students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;feb-9-2018&quot;&gt;Feb 9, 2018.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why are there rice noodles on the roof of Newell Simon Hall&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You konw spring is coming when the snow on Newell Simon Hall’s rooftop becomes
rice noodle (image on the right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/02-09-18-nsh.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/02-09-18-ricenoodle.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image source of the second photos &lt;a href=&quot;http://img64.foodjx.com/2/20140613/635382652704010391624.jpg&quot;&gt;http://img64.foodjx.com/2/20140613/635382652704010391624.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sep-28-2017&quot;&gt;Sep 28, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Computer Science at CMU is not just for boys&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find interesting things in restrooms! Here’s what I found in girls’
restroom on 5th floor in Gates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/09-28-17-boysclub.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it sounds great, I think they should have put it in boys’ restroom or
on a public wall. I believe the intention was to encourage
women to pursue computer science if that’s what they have been wanted to do. But
the point I wanted to make is that women, maybe especially female graduate
students, here at CMU are already brave enough to make it this far. We should
not only focus on encouraging women, but also educate our male colleagues and
build a friendly environment where woment don’t have to be encouraged to pursue
their favourite subject. If CMU CS is gender inclusive, women can feel it. We
don’t need to be reminded by a sign in a single restroom. If gender
inclusiveness is something that CMU CS is proud of, then I wish to see this sign
in a public space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sep-21-2017&quot;&gt;Sep 21, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How to pull an all-nighter in 5 minutes?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, have you pulled an all-nighter? NO?? You were too busy sleeping and forgot
to stay awake all night pretending to work hard? Well, when you walk into the
classroom, everyone will look like a panda except for you. You will look like an
outsider!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry. We’ve got you covered. If you go to the girls’ restroom on the 4th
floor in Gates, you will see everything you need. Free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/09-21-17-allnighter.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sep-19-2017&quot;&gt;Sep 19, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Happy smiley’s 35’s birthday!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know who invented :-)? Where was :-) first used?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 19 Sep, 1982, way before the emoji era, Scott Fahlman at CMU decided that people should use :-) for happy
feeling and :-( for sad feeling. When they could only communicate through plain
text, this was the cleverest idea. Now we have emoji, but I’d say text emoticons
are still very useful and efficient. &lt;a href=&quot;http://cool-smileys.com/text-emoticons&quot;&gt;Here’s a
list of text emoticons&lt;/a&gt;. (^o^)/ (◕‿◕✿)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, do you know why CMU’s computer science ranks 1st? Because we invented bug
swatter that can help our students quickly identify bugs so as to accelerate our
research progress!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/09-19-17-smiley.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/09-19-17-scott.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sep-14-2017&quot;&gt;Sep 14, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;CMU is hiring!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job description: clear the steep, overgrown hillside between the Gates Center
and Purnell Center for the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job compensation: tons of fress leaves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know who got the job? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cmu.edu/piper/news/archives/2017/september/grazing-goats.html&quot;&gt;A
group of goats!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/09-14-17-goat.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some unknown reasons, there was also a donkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aug-16-2017&quot;&gt;Aug 16, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;First day in my new office! May the source code be with you!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/08-16-17-source.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 15:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/cmu/CMU-life</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/cmu/CMU-life</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>CMU</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
