<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>STRUDEL</title>
    <description>The Socio-Technical Research Using Data Excavation Lab at Carnegie Mellon University</description>
    <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://cmustrudel.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 21:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 21:09:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Announcement: Papers accepted at ICSE 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Christmas came early this year, with four papers accepted at 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://conf.researchr.org/home/icse-2019&quot;&gt;ICSE 2019&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tool Choice Matters: JavaScript Quality Assurance Tools and Usage Outcomes in GitHub Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BugSwarm: Mining and Continuously Growing a Dataset of Reproducible Failures and Fixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Socio-Technical Work-Rate Increase Associates With Changes in Work Patterns in Online Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going Farther Together: The Impact of Social Capital on Sustained Participation in Open Source&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preprints are coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 12:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/announcement/icse-2019-papers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/announcement/icse-2019-papers</guid>
        
        
        <category>Announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travis: Travel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest and greatest of our travel adventures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/159982920@N04/albums/72157702982809092&quot; title=&quot;Travel&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7919/39984210273_b9d11be9bc_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;Travel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 16:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/travis/travel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/travis/travel</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travis</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: STRUDEL Reading Group updates</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-july-25-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, July 25, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So sad. Today was the last group meeting of the summer season.
Thanks a lot to our REU students Sophie and Courtney for spending their
summer with us. We appreciate your visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s all of us wearing STRUDEL gear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;flickr&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;flickr&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4893/33073145978_1607c959da_b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4893/33073145978_1607c959da_m.jpg 240w, https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4893/33073145978_1607c959da_n.jpg 320w, https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4893/33073145978_1607c959da.jpg 500w, https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4893/33073145978_1607c959da_z.jpg 640w, https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4893/33073145978_1607c959da_c.jpg 800w, https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4893/33073145978_1607c959da_b.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;license&quot;&gt;&amp;copy; Flickr/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/159982920@N04/33073145978/&quot;&gt;cmustrudel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;All Rights Reserved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;flickr&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;flickr&quot; src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4821/33073145848_3459741da4_b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4821/33073145848_3459741da4_m.jpg 240w, https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4821/33073145848_3459741da4_n.jpg 320w, https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4821/33073145848_3459741da4.jpg 500w, https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4821/33073145848_3459741da4_z.jpg 640w, https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4821/33073145848_3459741da4_c.jpg 800w, https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4821/33073145848_3459741da4_b.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;license&quot;&gt;&amp;copy; Flickr/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/159982920@N04/33073145848/&quot;&gt;cmustrudel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;All Rights Reserved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-june-27-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, June 27, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our REU student Courtney volunteered to present the paper &lt;b&gt;Do Programmers Work
at Night or During the Weekend&lt;/b&gt; (Claes et al., ICSE, 2018).
Being a college freshman, Courtney did a wonderful job presenting this
paper. 
There are several different types of visualisation in this paper and we
discussed their merits and defects.
Hopefully Courtney would find these examples useful when she has to present her work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie brought a piece of raspberry dark chocolate and a piece of 92% dark
chocolate. She presented the chocolate without any lable and left them to her
lab mates to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-june-20-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, June 20, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Widder presented the paper &lt;b&gt;Prevalence of Confusing Code in Software
Projects&lt;/b&gt; (Gopstein et al., MSR, 2018). I really like this paper especially
the confusing code they presented in the paper. Honestly, I think some of them
are fun to be kept in the code. They can sift out those who do not have solid
background in the C language and keep only experts in the develop team. 
I do believe that projects like Linux require developers with C knowledge far
beyond what one can learn from some online C tutorial or a single semester
college course.
However,
I think it is also necessary to remove confusing code so that more people can
get involved in the developing process. After all, more often than not, some
pieces of code are excessively confusing, especially we now have the luxury to
sacrifice disk space for code clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davide brought some brownies and Sophie brought some Chinese rice cake for the
dragon boat festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-may-23-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, May 23, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks’ practice talks done by several STRUDEL members, Sophie Qiu, yes, her again, presented the
paper &lt;b&gt;Newcomers’ Barriers. . . Is That All? An Analysis of Mentors’ and
Newcomers’ Barriers in OSS Projects&lt;/b&gt; (Balali et al., CSCW, 2018).
The paper identified several barriers that mentors are facing in open source
software projects. There are many newly found barriers but I think some of them
can be combined with or subsumed under some old ones; some need more details or
real instances. 
I think the barriers that they had identified are important.
However, I wish to see more practical and concrete solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-april-25-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, April 25, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie Qiu presented the freshly baked paper &lt;b&gt;Competence-Confidence Gap: A
Threat to Female Developers’ Contribution on GitHub&lt;/b&gt; (Wang et al., ICSE,
2018).
The authors show that there is a Granger causality between female programmers’ raise of number
of followers and their pull requests on GitHub. They claim that this is because
the number of followers bridges women’s competence-confidence gap and reassures 
female programmer that their contribution will be welcomed and
valuable.
Although this sounds a potential solution to encourage women to make
contributions to open source softwares, the paper did not mention how these
woemn earned new followers in the first place. The only example vaguely
mentioned was that the female programmer looked cute, which is in fact not an
acknowledgement of her programming ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-april-4-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, April 4, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alan Jaffe presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://victorialin.net/pubs/tellina_tr_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;Program Synthesis from Natural Language Using
Recurrent Neural Networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Lin et al., UW-CSE, 2017).
We often say there are two major coding styles: stackoverflow oriented
programming and google oriented programming.
The point it is making is that all the code we need are written, programmers
only need to assemble them to make a executable program.
I believe this can be easily replaced by machines and this paper is a proof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-march-28-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, March 28, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marat Valiet presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1802.07068.pdf&quot;&gt;Talent vs Luck: the role of
randomness in success and failure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.
This paper is a cool example of using simulation to address real life problems.
With a simple design they were able to model different funding policies and
their outcome. The paper claims that in some setups with a large influence of
luck, strategies based on random choices are more effective than traditional
“naively meritocratic” models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow people had forgotten our good tradition of bringing snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-march-21-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, March 21, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bogdan Vasilescu presented the paper &lt;b&gt;Was my contribution fairly
reviewed?” A Framework to Study the Perception of Fairness in Modern Code
Reviews&lt;/b&gt; (Yang, ICSE, 2018). In the paper, many different aspects of fairness are discussed,
which was very inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-feburary-21-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, Feburary 21, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Lacomis presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hal.inria.fr/hal-01691496/file/SEIP_63_Camera-Ready-no-copyright.pdf&quot;&gt;How
to Design a Program Repair Bot? Insights from
the Repairnator Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Urli et al. ICSE 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to learn about online program repair bugs. When I was talking
with a CMU undergrad at one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/cmukgb/&quot;&gt;KGB&lt;/a&gt;’s activity, he was excited
to learn that people are working on how to fix bugs automatically since he has
some very unpleasant experience with debugging - so do many of us. It would be
great if we could have a bug repairing bot with high accuracy in the future.
However, as Marat pointed out, when the debugging process can be largely
substituted by a robot, that means this language is dying. One example is
Assembly. Here’s a quote from Paul Graham
about the evolution of programming languages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What programmers in a hundred years will be looking for, most of all, is a
language where you can throw together an unbelievably inefficient version 1 of a
program with the least possible effort. At least, that’s how we’d describe it in
present-day terms. What they’ll say is that they want a language that’s easy to
program in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inefficient software isn’t gross. What’s gross is a language that makes
programmers do needless work. Wasting programmer time is the true inefficiency,
not wasting machine time. This will become ever more clear as computers get
faster.” (source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/hundred.html&quot;&gt;http://www.paulgraham.com/hundred.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-feburary-14-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, Feburary 14, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Yanwen Lin presented the paper
&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://haiyizhu.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/predicting-member-productivity-1.pdf&quot;&gt;Predicting
Member Productivity and Withdrawal from
Pre-Joining Attachments in Online Production Groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Yu et al. CSCW 17).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper analysed withdrawl from Wikipedia groups using the attachment
theories from social psychology. 
There results show that pre-joining connections are important to online
production groups. Speaking from my personal experience, I totally agree with
the authors. Especially in online community, when you often interact with people
who you don’t konw much personal information, it can be hard to form attachment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-feburary-7-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, Feburary 7, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shurui Zhou presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gustavopinto.org/lost+found/icse2018.pdf&quot;&gt;Almost There: A Study on
Quasi-Contributors in Open-Source Software Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Steinmarcher et al.,
ICSE 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to learn that many people stopped making further
contribution on GitHub after their first pull request was rejected. We also felt
that there would be many future work worth pursuing. Thanks Shurui’s
presentation as well as her snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was Alex’s meeting before he became a
professor in Estonia, he also brought some
pastries from Gates. We appreciated his intention of getting us fat. We will
miss you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, I think Gates’ blueberry muffin is very nice, as well as banana &amp;amp;
nuts in Scott. Nevertheless, no muffin compares to thos in Brown’s Blue Room or
banana muffin at Corner Bakery Cafe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-janurary-14-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, Janurary 14, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Widder presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ir.library.oregonstate.edu/downloads/wh246x964&quot;&gt;Open Source
barriers to entry, revisited: A tools perspective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Mendez et al. ICSE 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Margaret Burnett’s team has been studying GitHub’s gender inclusive
issues. Since men and women are biologically different statistically, tools
should be designed to cater their different ways of thinking and engaging with
software. I do not think software developing is an inheritly male dominated task. I
believe that getting
more women into software developing is a key to gender equality. Yes, I am a
feminist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davis is very good at baking, but I think he should have given out his delicious
brownies at the beginning of his presentation rather than at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;thusday-december-5-2017&quot;&gt;Thusday, December 5, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie Qiu presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1071581916301033&quot;&gt;The influence of visual feedback and
gender dynamics on performance,
perception and communication strategies in CSCW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Koulouri et al.
International Journal of Human-Computer Studies 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper shows that while men are statistically better at navigation with help
from visual signals, women can use verbal communication to compensate such
weakness and achieve the same level of excellency in navitation tasks.
GenderMag, which David Widder will present later, is in the same mindset that
although men and women are statistically biologically different, well-designed
tools can help both of them succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie did not know that green been pie could contain cream so she bought a lot
of them. Luckily, she could bring them to Strudel meetings so that everyone can
eat them and be merry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-28-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 28, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bogdan Vasilescu presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8031982/&quot;&gt;Code Coverage and Postrelease
Defects: A Large-Scale Study on Open Source Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Kochhar et al. 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper shows that code coverage in testing has insignificant correlation
with the number of bugs at the project level of a software. Then my question
was: how much test would be sufficient if a large software project could never be
bug-free?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not remember what snack we had during that meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-21-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 21, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shurui Zhou presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3104225&quot;&gt;Some from here, some from
there: cross-project code reuse in GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Gharehyazie et al., MSR 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper reminds me of two most popular ways of coding: Google-oriented coding
and stackoverflow-oriented coding. It is expensive to write code from scratch,
so understanding how code pieces are cloned across projects is useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not quite remember the snack but it might be Shurui’s Choco Pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-14-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 14, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexander Nolte presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hci.stanford.edu/publications/2017/flashorgs/flash-orgs-chi-2017.pdf&quot;&gt;Flash Organizations:
Crowdsourcing Complex Work by Structuring Crowds As Organizations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a nice paper on how to more effectively form an software developing group.
It was good to read some paper on HCI, which I was fascinated in but knew very
little about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your cookies, Alex. I guess they came from La Prima Espresso in
WEAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-7-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 7, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alan Jaffe presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1708.09492.pdf&quot;&gt;Automatically Generating Commit Messages
from Diffs Using Neural Machine Translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Jiang et al., ASE
2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an interesting application of the naturalness of code. I
learned a lot about the idea of naturalness of code, as well as the fact
that Alan is very good at baking pumpkin pies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-31-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 31, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No meeting this week. STRUDEL was away attending 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://ase2017.org&quot;&gt;ASE&lt;/a&gt; in Urbana-Champaign, IL and visiting
Fiona at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/cincinnatizoo/&quot;&gt;Cincinnati Zoo&lt;/a&gt;.
#teamfiona&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;flickr&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;flickr&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/854/43180283944_379c88bef1_b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/854/43180283944_379c88bef1_m.jpg 240w, https://farm1.staticflickr.com/854/43180283944_379c88bef1_n.jpg 320w, https://farm1.staticflickr.com/854/43180283944_379c88bef1.jpg 500w, https://farm1.staticflickr.com/854/43180283944_379c88bef1_z.jpg 640w, https://farm1.staticflickr.com/854/43180283944_379c88bef1_c.jpg 800w, https://farm1.staticflickr.com/854/43180283944_379c88bef1_b.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;license&quot;&gt;&amp;copy; Flickr/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/159982920@N04/43180283944/&quot;&gt;cmustrudel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;All Rights Reserved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-24-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 24, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STRUDEL was proud to host &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.win.tue.nl/~aserebre/&quot;&gt;Alexander 
Serebrenik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; from TU Eindhoven, who talked about his recent work on mining 
emotions from software engineering artifacts.
We were all enjoying his talk as well as Sophie’s hazelnut wafel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;flickr&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;flickr&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1797/42993926095_5da646eee1_b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1797/42993926095_5da646eee1_m.jpg 240w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1797/42993926095_5da646eee1_n.jpg 320w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1797/42993926095_5da646eee1.jpg 500w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1797/42993926095_5da646eee1_z.jpg 640w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1797/42993926095_5da646eee1_c.jpg 800w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1797/42993926095_5da646eee1_b.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;license&quot;&gt;&amp;copy; Flickr/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/159982920@N04/42993926095/&quot;&gt;cmustrudel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;All Rights Reserved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-17-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 17, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~fmri/plosone/files/hp_PLOS_ONE.pdf&quot;&gt;Simultaneously
Uncovering the Patterns of
Brain Regions Involved in Different Story
Reading Subprocesses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Wehbe et al., PLoS ONE 2014).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers scanned participants brains while they were reading
the ninth chapter of &lt;i&gt;Harry Potter and the Sorcerer’s Stone&lt;/i&gt;. They
then trained a classifier that can distinguish which short passage the
participants were reading based on the neural activity. The choice of
this paper was to present group members another machine learning
classifier that can process fMRI results. 
It was very nice and sweet that David made apple raisin strudels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;flickr&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;flickr&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1837/43180283674_28b7c4d9d9_b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1837/43180283674_28b7c4d9d9_m.jpg 240w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1837/43180283674_28b7c4d9d9_n.jpg 320w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1837/43180283674_28b7c4d9d9.jpg 500w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1837/43180283674_28b7c4d9d9_z.jpg 640w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1837/43180283674_28b7c4d9d9_c.jpg 800w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1837/43180283674_28b7c4d9d9_b.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;license&quot;&gt;&amp;copy; Flickr/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/159982920@N04/43180283674/&quot;&gt;cmustrudel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;All Rights Reserved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-10-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 10, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marat presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://delivery.acm.org/10.1145/2540000/2531642/p831-backstrom.pdf?ip=24.238.13.130&amp;amp;id=2531642&amp;amp;acc=OA&amp;amp;key=4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E528920FC4509E774&amp;amp;CFID=993659916&amp;amp;CFTOKEN=60398709&amp;amp;__acm__=1509333674_18432c45ea35e7515bb15ff9492d27f0&quot;&gt;Romantic partnerships and the
dispersion of social ties: a network analysis of relationship status on
facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Backstrom et al, CSCW 2014).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper proposed to use
dispersion, which measures “the extent to which two people’s mutual
friends are not themselves well-connected,” in addition to embeddedness,
which measures the number of mutural friends, to predict if two Facebook users 
are in a romantic relationship. The accuracy of prediction increased 
significantly when using the dispersion metric.
Somehow, my impression of the paper smells like homemade banana bread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-3-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 3, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://yuchi1989.github.io/papers/fse17-ErrDoc.pdf&quot;&gt;Automatically
Diagnosing and Repairing Error Handling Bugs in C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Tian and Ray, ESEC/FSE 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper presents how to identify different types of bugs and how to correct
them in C/C++ code. 
Happy Mid-autumn festival and thanks Sophie for her mooncake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;flickr&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;flickr&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1793/42993925755_26aa2b1f4f_b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1793/42993925755_26aa2b1f4f_m.jpg 240w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1793/42993925755_26aa2b1f4f_n.jpg 320w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1793/42993925755_26aa2b1f4f.jpg 500w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1793/42993925755_26aa2b1f4f_z.jpg 640w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1793/42993925755_26aa2b1f4f_c.jpg 800w, https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1793/42993925755_26aa2b1f4f_b.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;license&quot;&gt;&amp;copy; Flickr/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/159982920@N04/42993925755/&quot;&gt;cmustrudel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;All Rights Reserved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-september-26-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, September 26, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy presented the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.eecs.umich.edu/~weimerw/p/weimer-icse2017-preprint.pdf&quot;&gt;Decoding the representation of code in the
brain: An fMRI study of code review and expertise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Floyd et al, ICSE 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers scanned participants’ brain while they were reviewing code or 
prose. The findings suggest that reading code differs from reading natural 
language, but less so for experts than for novices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-september-19-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, September 19, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had our first reading group meeting today! To celebrate, Bogdan brought 
apple-cinnamon strudels for us. Nevertheless, these strudles were not as
good as our discussion on the paper &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.cs.umass.edu/~ameli/projects/fairness/papers/discriminationTesting.pdf&quot;&gt;Fairness Testing: 
Testing Software for Discrimination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Galhotra et al, ESEC/FSE 2017) that 
Bogdan presented at the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;flickr&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;flickr&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/941/42993925555_945c115392_b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/941/42993925555_945c115392_m.jpg 240w, https://farm1.staticflickr.com/941/42993925555_945c115392_n.jpg 320w, https://farm1.staticflickr.com/941/42993925555_945c115392.jpg 500w, https://farm1.staticflickr.com/941/42993925555_945c115392_z.jpg 640w, https://farm1.staticflickr.com/941/42993925555_945c115392_c.jpg 800w, https://farm1.staticflickr.com/941/42993925555_945c115392_b.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;license&quot;&gt;&amp;copy; Flickr/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/159982920@N04/42993925555/&quot;&gt;cmustrudel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;All Rights Reserved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 15:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/reading-group-meeting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/reading-group-meeting</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>reading-group</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
