<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>STRUDEL</title>
    <description>The Socio-Technical Research Using Data Excavation Lab at Carnegie Mellon University</description>
    <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://cmustrudel.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 19:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 19:11:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: STRUDEL Reading Group - Simultaneously Uncovering the Patterns of Brain Regions Involved in Different Story Reading Subprocesses</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sophie Qiu presented the paper &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~fmri/plosone/files/hp_PLOS_ONE.pdf&quot;&gt;Simultaneously
Uncovering the Patterns of
Brain Regions Involved in Different Story
Reading Subprocesses&lt;/a&gt; Wehbe et al. PLoS ONE 9(11) (2014). 
The researchers scanned participants brains while they were reading
the ninth chapter of &lt;i&gt;Harry Potter and the Sorcerer’s Stone&lt;/i&gt;. They
then trained a classifier that can distinguish which short passage the
participants were reading based on the neural activity. The choice of
this paper was to present group members another machine learning
classifier that can process fMRI results. 
It was very nice and sweet that David Widder made apple raisin strudels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 23:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/Sophie-harry-potter</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/Sophie-harry-potter</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>reading-group</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: STRUDEL Reading Group - Romantic partnerships and the dispersion of social ties: a network analysis of relationship status on facebook</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Marat Valiev presented the paper &lt;a href=&quot;http://delivery.acm.org/10.1145/2540000/2531642/p831-backstrom.pdf?ip=24.238.13.130&amp;amp;id=2531642&amp;amp;acc=OA&amp;amp;key=4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E528920FC4509E774&amp;amp;CFID=993659916&amp;amp;CFTOKEN=60398709&amp;amp;__acm__=1509333674_18432c45ea35e7515bb15ff9492d27f0&quot;&gt;Romantic partnerships and the
dispersion of social ties: a network analysis of relationship status on
facebook&lt;/a&gt; (Backstrom et al. Proc. of CSCW 831-841(2014)). This paper proposed to use
dispersion, which measures “the extent to which two people’s mutual
friends are not themselves well-connected,” in addition to embeddedness,
which measures the number of mutural friends, to
predict if two people are in a romantic relationship. The accuracy of
prediction increased significantly when using the dispersion metric.
Somehow, my impression of the paper smells like homemade banana bread.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 23:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/Morat-romantic-partners-facebook</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/Morat-romantic-partners-facebook</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>reading-group</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: STRUDEL reading group - Automatically Diagnosing and Repairing Error Handling Bugs in C</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;David Widder presented the paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://yuchi1989.github.io/papers/fse17-ErrDoc.pdf&quot;&gt;Automatically
Diagnosing and Repairing Error Handling Bugs in C&lt;/a&gt; (Tian and Ray. Proc. of FSE,
752-762(2017)). This paper
presents how to identify  different types of bugs and how to correct
them in C/C++ code. 
Happy Mid-autumn festival and thanks Sophie Qiu for her mooncake!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 23:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/David-repair-bug</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/David-repair-bug</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>reading-group</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
