<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>STRUDEL</title>
    <description>The Socio-Technical Research Using Data Excavation Lab at Carnegie Mellon University</description>
    <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://cmustrudel.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 20:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 20:17:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: CMU is FUN!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I came to the Open House in March 2017, I found that CMU is a nerdy but
cool space. 
People are smart and creative. As a result, my life at CMU has been full of
funny anecdots.
I wanted to share some of them that made me burst into laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feb 14, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My office mate brought the the issue of Valentine’s Day plan when she was
working with her collaborator. She told us if you brought your laptop to the
bookstore, they would clean it for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/02-14-18-valentine.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People celebrate Valentine’s Day with their valentines. Same here at CMU.
However, CMU might have defined valentine slightly differently. It expanded the
concept beyond human beings. Apart from your collaborators, people usually
interact the most&lt;br /&gt;
with their valentines. If we count objects as well, one’s laptop 
is definitely the number 1 valentine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 12:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/cmu/CMU-jokes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/cmu/CMU-jokes</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>CMU</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: STRUDEL Reading Group Updates</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-feburary-7-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, Feburary 7, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shurui Zhou presented the paper &lt;a href=&quot;http://gustavopinto.org/lost+found/icse2018.pdf&quot;&gt;Almost There: A Study on
Quasi-Contributors in Open-Source Software Projects&lt;/a&gt; (Steinmarcher et al.,
ICSE 2018). It was interesting to learn that many people stopped making further
contribution on GitHub after their first pull request was rejected. We also felt
that there would be many future work worth pursuing. Thanks Shurui’s
presentation as well as her snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was Alex’s meeting before he became a
professor in Estonia, he also brought some
pastries from Gates. We appreciated his intention of getting us fat. We will
miss you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, I think Gates’ blueberry muffin is very nice, as well as banana &amp;amp;
nuts in Scott. Nevertheless, no muffin compares to thos in Brown’s Blue Room or
banana muffin at Corner Bakery Cafe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wednesday-janurary-14-2018&quot;&gt;Wednesday, Janurary 14, 2018&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Widder presented the paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://ir.library.oregonstate.edu/downloads/wh246x964&quot;&gt;Open Source
barriers to entry, revisited: A tools perspective&lt;/a&gt; (Mendez et al. ICSE 2018).
Professor Margaret Burnett’s team has been studying GitHub’s gender inclusive
issues. Since men and women are biologically different statistically, tools
should be designed to cater their different ways of thinking and engaging with
software. I do not think software developing is an inheritly male dominated task. I
believe that getting
more women into software developing is a key to gender equality. Yes, I am a
feminist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davis is very good at baking, but I think he should have given out his delicious
brownies at the beginning of his presentation rather than at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;thusday-december-5-2017&quot;&gt;Thusday, December 5, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie Qiu presented the paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1071581916301033&quot;&gt;The influence of visual feedback and
gender dynamics on performance,
perception and communication strategies in CSCW&lt;/a&gt; (Koulouri et al.
International Journal of Human-Computer Studies 2017).
This paper shows that while men are statistically better at navigation with help
from visual signals, women can use verbal communication to compensate such
weakness and achieve the same level of excellency in navitation tasks.
GenderMag, which David Widder will present later, is in the same mindset that
although men and women are statistically biologically different, well-designed
tools can help both of them succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie did not know that green been pie could contain cream so she bought a lot
of them. Luckily, she could bring them to Strudel meetings so that everyone can
eat them and be merry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-28-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 28, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bogdan Vasilescu presented the paper &lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8031982/&quot;&gt;Code Coverage and Postrelease
Defects: A Large-Scale Study on Open Source Projects&lt;/a&gt; (Kochhar et al. 2017). 
This paper shows that code coverage in testing has insignificant correlation
with the number of bugs at the project level of a software. Then my question
was: how much test would be sufficient if a large software project could never be
bug-free?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not remember what snack we had during that meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-21-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 21, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shurui Zhou presented the paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3104225&quot;&gt;Some from here, some from
there: cross-project code reuse in GitHub&lt;/a&gt; (Gharehyazie et al., MSR 2017).
This paper reminds me of two most popular ways of coding: Google-oriented coding
and stackoverflow-oriented coding. It is expensive to write code from scratch,
so understanding how code pieces are cloned across projects is useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not quite remember the snack but it might be Choco Pie brought by Shurui.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-14-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 14, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexander Nolte presented the paper &lt;a href=&quot;http://hci.stanford.edu/publications/2017/flashorgs/flash-orgs-chi-2017.pdf&quot;&gt;Flash Organizations:
Crowdsourcing Complex Work by Structuring Crowds As Organizations&lt;/a&gt;.
It is a nice paper on how to more effectively form an software developing group.
It was good to read some paper on HCI, which I was fascinated in but knew very
little about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your cookies, Alex. I guess they came from La Prima Espresso in
WEAN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-november-7-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, November 7, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alan Jaffe presented the paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1708.09492.pdf&quot;&gt;Automatically Generating Commit Messages
from Diffs Using Neural Machine Translation&lt;/a&gt; (Jiang et al., ASE
2017). It is an interesting application of the naturalness of code. I
learned a lot about the idea of naturalness of code, as well as the fact
that Alan is very good at baking pumpkin pies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-31-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 31, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No meeting this week. STRUDEL was away attending 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://ase2017.org&quot;&gt;ASE&lt;/a&gt; in Urbana-Champaign, IL and visiting
Fiona at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/cincinnatizoo/&quot;&gt;Cincinnati Zoo&lt;/a&gt;.
#teamfiona&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/10-31-17-fiona.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-24-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 24, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STRUDEL was proud to host &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.win.tue.nl/~aserebre/&quot;&gt;Alexander 
Serebrenik&lt;/a&gt; from TU Eindhoven, who talked about his recent work on mining 
emotions from software engineering artifacts.
We were all enjoying his talk as well as Sophie’s hazelnut wafel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/10-24-17-serebrenik.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-17-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 17, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie presented the paper “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~fmri/plosone/files/hp_PLOS_ONE.pdf&quot;&gt;Simultaneously
Uncovering the Patterns of
Brain Regions Involved in Different Story
Reading Subprocesses&lt;/a&gt;” (Wehbe et al., PLoS ONE 2014). 
The researchers scanned participants brains while they were reading
the ninth chapter of &lt;i&gt;Harry Potter and the Sorcerer’s Stone&lt;/i&gt;. They
then trained a classifier that can distinguish which short passage the
participants were reading based on the neural activity. The choice of
this paper was to present group members another machine learning
classifier that can process fMRI results. 
It was very nice and sweet that David made apple raisin strudels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/10-17-17-strudel.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-10-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 10, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marat presented the paper “&lt;a href=&quot;http://delivery.acm.org/10.1145/2540000/2531642/p831-backstrom.pdf?ip=24.238.13.130&amp;amp;id=2531642&amp;amp;acc=OA&amp;amp;key=4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E4D4702B0C3E38B35%2E528920FC4509E774&amp;amp;CFID=993659916&amp;amp;CFTOKEN=60398709&amp;amp;__acm__=1509333674_18432c45ea35e7515bb15ff9492d27f0&quot;&gt;Romantic partnerships and the
dispersion of social ties: a network analysis of relationship status on
facebook&lt;/a&gt;” (Backstrom et al, CSCW 2014). This paper proposed to use
dispersion, which measures “the extent to which two people’s mutual
friends are not themselves well-connected,” in addition to embeddedness,
which measures the number of mutural friends, to predict if two Facebook users 
are in a romantic relationship. The accuracy of prediction increased 
significantly when using the dispersion metric.
Somehow, my impression of the paper smells like homemade banana bread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-october-3-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, October 3, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David presented the paper “&lt;a href=&quot;https://yuchi1989.github.io/papers/fse17-ErrDoc.pdf&quot;&gt;Automatically
Diagnosing and Repairing Error Handling Bugs in C&lt;/a&gt;” (Tian and Ray, ESEC/FSE 2017). 
This paper presents how to identify different types of bugs and how to correct
them in C/C++ code. 
Happy Mid-autumn festival and thanks Sophie for her mooncake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/10-03-17-moon.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-september-26-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, September 26, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy presented the paper “&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.eecs.umich.edu/~weimerw/p/weimer-icse2017-preprint.pdf&quot;&gt;Decoding the representation of code in the
brain: An fMRI study of code review and expertise&lt;/a&gt;” (Floyd et al, ICSE 2017). 
The researchers scanned participants’ brain while they were reviewing code or 
prose. The findings suggest that reading code differs from reading natural 
language, but less so for experts than for novices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tuesday-september-19-2017&quot;&gt;Tuesday, September 19, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had our first reading group meeting today! To celebrate, Bogdan brought 
apple-cinnamon strudels for us. Nevertheless, these strudles were not as
good as our discussion on the paper “&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.cs.umass.edu/~ameli/projects/fairness/papers/discriminationTesting.pdf&quot;&gt;Fairness Testing: 
Testing Software for Discrimination&lt;/a&gt;” (Galhotra et al, ESEC/FSE 2017) that 
Bogdan presented at the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/09-19-17-group.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 17:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/reading-group-meeting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/blog/reading-group/reading-group-meeting</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>reading-group</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Announcement: Paper presented at ASE 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We were at &lt;a href=&quot;http://ase2017.org&quot;&gt;ASE 2017&lt;/a&gt; presenting the paper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Impact of Continuous Integration on Other Software Development Practices: 
A Large-Scale Empirical Study&lt;/strong&gt;,
with &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=PqQtwvIAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Yangyang Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.win.tue.nl/~aserebre/&quot;&gt;Alexander Serebrenik&lt;/a&gt;, Yuming Zhou, and 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cs.ucdavis.edu/~filkov/&quot;&gt;Vladimir Filkov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details about the research &lt;a href=&quot;../../projects/continuous-integration/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
PDF &lt;a href=&quot;../../papers/ase17ci.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Slides &lt;a href=&quot;../../slides/ase17ci.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pics/10-31-17-yangyang.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cmustrudel.github.io/announcement/ase-paper</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cmustrudel.github.io/announcement/ase-paper</guid>
        
        
        <category>Announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
